[Music]
welcome back to the channel
i'm nick and today we're gonna make a
salton straw
recipe it's an exact copy of their
salted malted chocolate chip cookie
dough
that's a name and a half this recipe is
direct from the masters at salt and
straw themselves
so if you want to see how it's done
stick with us
[Music]
now to make the base it's a molasses
vanilla
ice cream soda describe what you're
going to do is combine your sugar your
milk powder salt and xanthan gum in a
bowl
and stir it really well and that's just
to distribute the xanthan gum evenly
in a pot over medium heat combine the
milk corn syrup molasses
whisk it all until well combined add
your
dry mixture and whisk very well until
there are no more lumps
cook it for 2-3 minutes until the sugar
is all dissolved and then remove it from
the heat
pour that mixture into a large container
and then add in your cream and vanilla
cover it and refrigerate for at least
four hours before churning
[Music]
to make the malted cookie dough in a
large bowl cream together your
butter the two sugars and salt with a
spoon until it all combines nicely then
add your cream
molasses corn syrup if that's what
you're using here
and vanilla and then just keep turning
add your toasted flour and your mold
powder to the mix and keep going until
there's no lumps finally fold in your
chocolate
and spread it out onto a tin lined with
parchment paper
and then pop it in the freezer for at
least an hour until it's solid
when it's ready take out the freezer and
chop it up into tiny little cubes pop it
back in the freezer until you're ready
to use it
this is the malted fudge mix together
your water and malt powder together in a
small pot
add your corn syrup heavy cream butter
and finally the salt
then heat it up until the butter is
completely melted and the mixture starts
to come to a boil
at that point remove it from the heat
and finally add the cocoa powder and
your chopped chocolate
and whisk it thoroughly until all
combined and the chocolate is fully
melted
at that point transfer it to an airtight
container where you can store it in the
fridge
[Music]
once that's done for me it was 15 20
minutes but for you it could be anything
up to 30 depending on your machine
start loading it into your tub and layer
in your ice cream
your fudge and your cookie dough well
don't skimp on putting all the
ingredients in
load it up nicely once that's done put
the lid on put it back in your freezer
until you're ready to eat it i recommend
at least
three hours in the freezer
[Music]
the ice cream has been in the freezer
overnight we're going to dish some up
and see what it looks like
[Music]
so we don't get salt and straw ice cream
in the uk
i've never had it it some of their
flavors look great sound great
so i just wanted to try this one it's a
combination that i've never
even considered so here we go i'm not a
massive fan of cookie dough
but this one did smell really good
making it so
let's just dig in and see what it's like
[Music]
that is good it's a great recipe
the ice cream's got really nice texture
to it there's there's no iciness i mean
all balanced recipes should should be
like that anyway but
just goes to show that salt and straw
know what they're doing there's a lot of
companies out there making ice cream and
it's rubbish
but this isn't one of them this is
really good you get a little bit of
saltiness in the background not too much
just enough to kind of enhance the other
flavors the malt
i didn't use the same malt that they
used i just used a malt
drink type to be fair i probably could
have used something a little bit
stronger
but it still does come through the fudge
is really nice not overpowering flavor
the cookie dough i actually really like
this one
the i can taste some elastic it's got
molasses in it so i can taste that
coming through but it's not overpowering
it doesn't
make everything else bitter it's a
really nice kind of combination of
flavors
would i change anything in this recipe
apart from a stronger mold flavor
so maybe some malt for brewing or
something like that i don't know i don't
drink beer so
who knows what goes in it but um
yeah that's that's about it
that cookie does really good i'm
surprising myself
i hate cookie dough the last cookie
dough ice cream
my wife had to eat the whole thing
because i'm just not fan of it
but i would safe to say that this ice
cream is actually in
you know top 10 currently for me nice
one salt straw did a really good job
we will definitely make another ice
cream of yours in the future
if you've got a flavor that you want to
see us make hit us down in the comments
below make sure to like and subscribe
thanks very much for watching and we'll
see you next time
[Music]